# Nolan Frame

frame.nolan@gmail.com | (406) 531-8007 | Seattle, WA | he/him/his

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/framenolan | GitHub: https://github.com/framenolan

Portfolio: https://framenolan-portfolio.herokuapp.com

## **Summary**

Full-stack Web Developer driven by creative problem solving, elevating user experience, and process improvement. Combining newly acquired coding skill with 10 years of experience as a project lead in business operations and a Bachelor's degree in Business Administration through the Business Leadership Program. Thrive in a deadline-driven environment, and excel at learning new concepts quickly.

### **Technical Skills**

- Front-End: HTML, CSS, JavaScript (ES6), React, jQuery, Bootstrap
- <u>Back-End</u>: Express, Node, REST API, MySQL, MongoDB, JSON, GraphQL
- <u>Utility</u>: Git, Heroku, Google Suite, Microsoft Office Suite

# **Projects**

Star Arcade Front-End Developer & Designer

Repo: <a href="https://bit.ly/3tPrtcm">https://bit.ly/3y6gsWH</a>

- Collection of arcade-style games built using React.js
- Built Flappy Bird clone in React, and partnered on look and feel of entire app
- Lead designer for look and feel of website
- Tools/Languages: React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Socket.io, Express, MySQL2

Where's The Beer?

Front-End Developer & Lead Designer

Repo: <a href="https://bit.ly/3tPs5ia">https://bit.ly/3tPs5ia</a> | Deployed: <a href="https://bit.ly/3b7GsrD">https://bit.ly/3b7GsrD</a>

- Mobile-responsive brewery directory web app that provides user driving directions to selected brewery
- Combines <u>Open Brewery DB</u> with <u>Google Maps</u> to return search results from the brewery API and load them onto a map, with driving directions and ability to save favorites
- Winner of Best Functionality Award
- Tools/Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Moment.js, Bulma CSS Framework

Buddygram

Back-End Lead Developer

Repo: <a href="https://bit.lv/3QzmQqA">https://bit.lv/3QzmQqA</a> | Deployed: <a href="https://bit.lv/39HfCq3">https://bit.lv/3QzmQqA</a> | Deployed: <a href="https://bit.lv/39HfCq3">https://bit.lv/39HfCq3</a>

- Social network for inviting or responding to activities and making new friends
- Developed RESTful API routes for user authentication, content posting and interaction
- Used Handlebars to render front-end components
- Tools/Languages: JavaScript, MySQL2, Sequelize, Express, Handlebars, bcrypt, Cloudinary, dotenv

## **Work Experience**

SHW

August 2021 - March 2022

Director, Event Technology & Chief Privacy Officer

Seattle, WA

 Oversaw Video Production line of business, producing livestream and pre-recorded events that included continuing education for dentists, multi-day customer conferences, and training. Events occurred across multiple time zones and languages.

- Configured NetSuite ERP as a financial operations platform by gathering requirements from cross-functional teams and directing implementation. Established both company-wide and individual contributor business processes for the new enterprise platform.
- Wrote, implemented, and enforced compliance policies that met GDPR standards.

# SHW

January 2017 - July 2021

Seattle, WA

**Business Operations Manager** 

- As Head of the IT Department managed the annual IT budget, reported to senior management and negotiated IT support and SaaS vendor contracts.
- Wrote and implemented standardized Operating Manual for event planning, including standard operating procedures and 15 templates.
- Optimized training and onboarding for new event managers.
- Redesigned budget template in Excel, reducing human errors that saved up to \$70k annually.

### SHW

September 2014 - January 2017

Project Manager & Salesforce Administrator

Seattle, WA

- Transitioned company from end-of-life SQL server to new custom-built Salesforce instance.
- Reduced expense report processing time by 60% with a custom-built, cloud-enabled process in Salesforce, providing real-time data that was more accurate and accessible.
- Built shift app automating time tracking and expenses for on-call staff, saved Payroll 10hrs per month.
- Led rebranding efforts under new CEO including a new company website on Squarespace and tasked to source a new logo design.

SHW

May 2012 - September 2014

Registration and Guest Services Coordinator

Seattle, WA

- Constructed event registration websites to collect attendee data and processed data for reports.
- Provided high quality customer service to clients, attendees, and partners.
- Maintained data integrity and privacy compliance while providing clients, vendors, and internal teams with necessary reports for successful event production.

## **Non-Technical Skills**

- Salesforce System Administration
- Public Speaking, Strong Written and Verbal Communication
- GDPR Compliance and Data Privacy

#### Education

University of Washington, Seattle, WA Certificate, Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp June 2022

University of Puget Sound, Tacoma, WA Bachelor of Arts, Business Administration Bachelor of Arts, Music

Business Leadership Program

May 2011